Eric King

kingeric027@gmail.com • 651.587.3105 • St. Paul, MN

Github: https://github.com/kingeric027 • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/eric-king-99803a85/ • Portfolio: https://kingeric027.github.io/My-Portfolio/Eric-King-Portfolio.html

Summary: Web developer with more than four years of experience as business intelligence analyst. Resourceful problem solver with ability to communicate technical information in concise and simple format. Recognized for ability to learn new skills quickly.

Technical Skills: Web Development, JavaScript, React, Node, Express HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, RESTful API, Git, Project Management, Business Intelligence, R Programming, Data Visualization, and Statistical Modeling.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, Coding Boot Camp, St. Paul, MN

January to March, 2019

- Completed intensive 24-week course dedicated to designing and building web applications while simultaneously working full time as business analyst.
- Created applications while employing numerous technologies and libraries, including Javascript, CSS, HTML, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, and React.

St. Olaf College, Northfield, MN

2010 to 2014

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics

- Earned bachelor's degree in mathematics with concentration in statistics.
- Selected by professors to be calculus tutor and homework grader for statistics course.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Exoplanet Web Application, https://kingeric027.github.io/Project-1/

- Worked with team to develop application to allow users to explore data on discovered planets.
- Utilized axios to query data from NASA API and Tabulator to display table of planets and Google Firebase to store selected data.
- Gained experience in project management. Coordinated with team to delegate required tasks and set deadlines.

React National Parks Game, https://kingeric027.github.io/National-parks-clicky-game/

• Built application with React to render images that are shuffled in their container following every click. Designed for the user to attempt to find distinct parks without clicking the same image twice.

Friend Finder Application, https://salty-crag-15358.herokuapp.com/

- Built application where users can fill out survey and be matched with compatible friend from database of other users.
- Used MySQL relational database to store survey data along with API routes to get and post data.
- Wrote JavaScript function to compare data to prior entries and return the most compatible friend.

Eric King, Page 2

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deluxe Corporation, Business Intelligence Analyst, Shoreview, MN

2015 to present

- Provided business leaders with detailed analysis of business trends utilizing SAS, R, Tableau
 Visualization and Microsoft Excel. Developed data-driven solutions to complex strategic questions.
- Performed deep-dive analysis of customer lifetime value. Used exponential decay model to estimate average lifetime of customers to drive more effective marketing strategy.
- Created interactive Price Increase Dashboard with Tableau Visualization to model and display the potential outcomes of proposed price increase.
- Developed new method to more accurately track churn rates of recurring products and wrote the necessary SAS script for implementation.

Deluxe Corporation, Human Resources Analytics Intern, Shoreview, MN

Summer 2014

- Worked alongside decision makers in Human Resources to uncover trends related to employee development and success at Deluxe.
- Constructed statistical models to develop profiles of the most successful employees.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Model 284, Contributor/Analyst, Minneapolis, MN

2016 to present

- Analyzed sports, developed website content, and predicted game outcomes by creating math and statistical models. Used multiple regression, logistic regression, and decision-tree modeling techniques to create:
 - NFL Combine R Shiny App: https://model284.com/nfl-combine-tool/
 - Wide Receiver Draft Model: https://model284.com/my-model-monday-wide-receiver-draft-model/
 - NBA Playoff Bracket and Simulation https://model284.com/2018-nba-playoff-bracket/
- Authored articles on www.model284.com explaining results and implications of data analysis.
- Invited to speak at St. Olaf College about the applications of statistics in sports.

Center for Interdisciplinary Research, Team Member, St. Olaf College

2011 to 2013

- Received stipend to conduct statistical research for St. Olaf professors and presented findings at National Conference for Undergraduate Research on two occasions.
- Created computer simulation of baseball games using random number simulation and Markov chains.
- Analyzed Alabama's census data from 1860 to 1870 and designed statistical models to predict racial violence and voting trends among counties.

ABOUT ME

My affinity for mathematics and solving puzzles has been a natural gateway into coding. I am transitioning careers from Business Analytics to Web Development because I want to design applications and have more creative freedom in my work. In my free time, I love playing basketball, snowboarding, and camping. I've also completed both the Twin Cities and Green Bay marathons.